Welcome to today's episode where we discuss the latest developments in artificial intelligence.
Large language models have been making significant progress in reasoning capabilities.
Companies like OpenAI and Google are competing to build the most capable models.
The compute requirements for training these models continue to grow exponentially.
New chip architectures from Nvidia and AMD are designed specifically for AI workloads.
The H100 GPU has become the standard hardware for training large models.
Meanwhile regulation of AI systems is becoming a major policy topic.
The European Union has passed the AI Act which creates new compliance requirements.
Companies must now classify their AI systems by risk level under the new framework.
In the United States Congress is still debating various approaches to AI governance.
Some lawmakers favor a light touch approach while others want strict regulations.
The debate around AI safety continues to intensify as models become more capable.
Researchers are working on alignment techniques to ensure AI systems behave as intended.
Constitutional AI and reinforcement learning from human feedback are two key approaches.
The open source community has also made impressive progress with models like Llama and Mistral.
These open models are enabling smaller companies and researchers to experiment with AI.
That wraps up our discussion for today. Thanks for watching and see you next time.